Sara Coren

PROFILE

I am a product driven full stack web developer excited about expanding my knowledge base in the field. I have been a life-long learner and elementary educator as well as a researcher, geoscientist and humanitarian. I am passionate about using my web development skills and human centered approach in design to help people around the world access information to improve the quality of their lives.

CONTACT



610.772.1279



sara.coren@gmail.com



Sara Coren



/saracoren



saracoren.io

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Bootstrap, Mongo, Heroku, Angular, Ruby on Rails, SQL, React, GitHub, Illustrator, ArcGIS

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

General Assembly

MASTERS in GENERAL and SPECIAL EDUCATION (Gr. 1-6)

Touro College

MASTERS in GEOGRAPHY and ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE

University College London

BACHELORS in GEOLOGY with a MINOR in SOCIOLOGY

The College of William & Mary

INTERESTS

UX Design, Innovation, Traveling, Hiking, Kayaking, Volunteering, Cross-Stitching

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive

March 2019 - June 2019 Stamford, Connecticut

- Learned full stack web development at General Assembly's Software
 Engineering Immersive including HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs,
 Bootstrap, Mongo, Heroku, Angular, Ruby on Rails, SQL, React, and GitHub
- Created a variety of web applications including project1, project 2, project 3

Rectory School | Grade 2 & 3 Lead Teacher

August 2017 - June 2018 Pomfret, Connecticut

- Instructed a mixed class of 2nd and 3rd grade students across all subject areas
- Wrote original curriculum and developed project based science lessons,
 activities and projects to help students connect their learning to the real world

Windham Public Schools | Substitute Math Coach & STEM Teacher

- August 2015 June 2017 Windham, Connecticut
- Worked as a math coach serving students in Grades K-5 with instructional support and providing data collection
- Substitute taught in various STEM classrooms in grades pre-K to 8

New York City Dept. of Education | Grade 4 Lead Teacher

August 2010 - June 2015 New York, New York

- Worked in a small coaching group for Literacy Coaches with Columbia Teachers College staff developers
- Gave professional development presentations to staff and served as president of the School Leadership Team
- Piloted the first Saturday Tutoring Program for struggling learners

United Nations | International Strategy for Disaster Reduction

June 2008 - August 2008 Geneva, Switzerland

- Worked with an international team as an Information Management Unit Intern and attended the International Disaster and Risk Conference
- Conducted interviews with over 200 participants from a variety of backgrounds including government, academia, non-profit, industrial, etc. in order to reveal networks of people working together within the disaster community

ImageCat Ltd | International Risk Management

June 2008 - September 2008 London, UK

- Served as a Collaborative Research Partner
- Conducted research and interviewed high ranking officials in emergency services in California and produced an 80+ page report, with an abridged selection appearing in a publication for the US National Science Foundation